He could still be alive.
No.
Move out of the way.
She died because of you.
If only I'd gone out sooner…
This is your fault.
You killed her.
ORIGINAL STORY SWEET HOME
BY CARNBY KIM AND YOUNGCHAN HWANG
You can't trust that announcement.
Will you really be okay?
We can't keep sponging off you.
We should do something.
Thank you for the meals and this.
May God bless you.
I'm Buddhist.
If the first floor is safe,
we'll come back to get you.
Don't make a promise you can't keep.
I feel like
I should say farewell now.
Someone once said that
even the thickest darkness
disappears with the faintest light.
Is the person who said that still alive?
I'm not sure.
I…
Can I go with you?
I guess three is better than two. Right?
Of course.
Okay.
Go.
Go. All of you.
Hyun-su, you have to come back, okay?
Okay.
Thank you for saving us.
Shall we get going?
Thank you.
Suddenly,
I'm like the head of a kindergarten.
AUGUST 18, 2020
DAY 4 OF CONFINEMENT
I'VE NEVER BEEN THIS GLAD TO HEAR
THE APARTMENT PA ANNOUNCEMENT
I WANTED TO GO AS SOON AS I HEARD HIM
URGE US TO GO DOWN TO THE FIRST FLOOR
I THINK WE SHOULD GO DOWN
FOR YU-RI'S SAKE
I think it's time to leave.
Not yet, sir.
I'm praying hard for you
to live a long life.
No, I didn't mean this world.
I meant here. This disgustingly small,
dirty old room.
But isn't this place
younger than you, sir?
How long have you been living here?
Let me see.
Hold on.
Was it since the independence
or the Korean War?
Your life has been extended just now.
I guess I won't die anytime soon
thanks to you.
What are you doing?
Didn't you hear the announcement?
I should go to the first floor to help.
Could you be of any help?
Careful.
She must be devastated.
If my Bom died,
I think I'd be devastated, too.
I think this is a little different.
No, it's not.
Bom is family to me.
Still,
it can't be the same
as losing your own child.
You don't have kids, either.
You wouldn't know what it's like.
-Right.
-Anyway, I feel really bad
for Ms. Cha and the firefighter lady.
What about her?
Her fiancé used to live here.
He died.
The wedding's supposed to be in two days.
What happened to him?
I don't know.
What do you think happened?
She seemed so poised. I had no idea.
But what's taking her so long?
Do you think something happened to her?
SANG-WON
Sang-won.
The cellphone's out of service anyway.
Exactly.
But how'd she know her daughter
was coming?
It's a mystery.
Do you think she's possessed?
Possessed? No, she's just crazy.
I feel bad for her.
Anyway,
you better watch out for Eun-hyeok.
That guy is totally heartless.
That's bullshit. He saved your life.
What are you talking about?
If he hadn't stopped you,
you'd be dead like that soldier.
Hey, Seok-hyeon.
It's so reassuring
to have you as the leader.
Leader, my ass. I don't want that job.
But we can't let that four-eyes
be the leader.
I'm glad you're okay.
You knew
there was a monster, didn't you?
Yi-kyung.
I was worried about you.
Are you okay?
This is not a drill.
BREAKING NEWS
As of 24:00 on August 17, 2020,
martial law has been declared
throughout the Republic of Korea
in accordance with Article 77, Section 1
of the Constitution and Article 2,
Section 2 of the Martial Law Act.
The military will be in charge
of all security and civil affairs.
The military has confirmed that
an unspecified number of people
have been turning into unknown creatures.
The exact cause is still unknown,
but it is believed
to be related to human desire.
It is not a respiratory
or blood-borne infection.
Quarantine those who show symptoms
of hypothermia,
nosebleeds, fainting, and auditory
or visual hallucinations.
These creatures have excellent
resilience and regenerative abilities.
Before an individual turns,
there is a period of time
when they cannot recover
from severe lacerations or damage.
It is the only time
these creatures can be killed.
We have thus termed this
the "golden hour."
All captured creatures
should be incinerated.
Currently, this is the only action
civilians can take.
The military can and will
solve the current situation.
Survive.
Good luck.
See? We're fine.
The military will come and rescue us
if we hold out.
I knew it.
She just told us to survive on our own.
Is that what she meant?
Desire makes you a monster?
-Does that make sense?
-You saw them roaming outside.
She told us to survive.
-That's what she meant, right?
-What?
That's it!
-But the president died.
-Is that really what she meant?
-Yes, of course.
-What do you mean by hold out?
-What?
-Do you really believe that?
-We all saw it.
-Pay back what you owe!
Seriously?
Is it okay to go downstairs like this?
Shouldn't we grab something useful?
The most useful thing is our lives.
It's a person.
I'm relieved to see a corpse.
It's still warm.
He hasn't been dead for long.
Oh, God.
Put it back if you don't want it.
-You're mean.
-Yes, I am.
I can do worse things to survive.
You're an accomplice now.
Let's go.
Don't die. Why did you die?
You can't leave me here all alone.
Don't die, please. I beg you.
MOON HYEON-SUK, CHA SU-A
-Is he dead?
-No.
He isn't dead.
I thought he'd die.
-Do you know him?
-No.
Don't go near him.
-We can't leave the infected here.
-Take this monster out.
Dad…
You really fell.
When I told you not to die here,
I meant the whole building.
Where am I?
It's a place where everyone gathered,
waiting to die.
What about the other two?
They're safe.
I guess you aren't as shitty as I thought.
You should worry about yourself, not them.
Pardon?
Eun-yu.
You're fine.
You fell from the 9th floor
and woke up in 3 hours.
Maybe the golden hour saved you.
Isn't it ironic?
The golden hour used to mean
the last hour to save someone.
Now it means the only possible period
of time to destroy someone.
How do you feel?
I think I'm okay.
Good.
It's going to be tough from here on out.
What is it?
Why did he call us?
-What?
-Keep going.
You're out of your mind.
You brought a frigging monster in here.
Don't you dare turn.
Got it? You fucking monster.
Answer when an adult speaks to you.
Got it.
-What?
-We can't do that.
I don't intend on missing the golden hour.
-The Lord said--
-I'm sure Jesus never lived
in a world like this, did He?
It's for everyone's safety.
Here.
What is that?
Each of you take a piece of paper.
If you think we should oust Hyun-su,
draw a circle.
And if you don't think we should,
draw an X.
Then put the paper in this box.
Obviously, he'll be kicked out.
Why bother?
Just do a show of hands. I want him out.
Who wants him out?
Why don't you raise your hand?
I don't.
You aren't old enough to vote.
Are we electing the president?
Age doesn't matter.
How dare you talk back?
When an adult says something,
you should shut up and agree.
FUCK BASTARDS LIKE YOU
Did you just swear at me?
I'm old enough to be your dad.
How dare you!
No, I didn't.
I said you're the best.
FUCK BASTARDS LIKE YOU
To protect everyone's privacy,
it must be a secret ballot.
What?
Because ousting him…
would be taking part in murder.
Privacy? My ass.
I want him out. Out!
Murder?
We're making this decision to survive.
Don't be scared!
Hey, aren't you going to raise your hand?
What? Well…
Raise your hand, you stupid cow.
I think Eun-hyeok has a point.
Isn't it better not to know
who agreed to oust him?
It's only natural to vote
in a democratic country.
Democracy? The world is coming to an end.
Stop calling your wife names
and using profanities.
It's very offensive.
Why you…
-How dare you tell me what--
-Enough.
IN FAVOR, 8
OPPOSED, 7
There are eight in favor
and seven opposed.
If one of the last two ballots is
in favor, he'll be ousted.
Seven people opposed?
Are you guys crazy?
Opposed.
It's eight to eight.
Damn it.
Did you oppose?
I didn't.
All the bitches and bastards on his side
should all be thrown out!
Hey, mister!
Don't get worked up yet.
This last vote will determine the result.
Invalid.
No way.
Hey, bring that bastard here.
Me?
Yes! We have to get rid of him
as fast as we can!
Voting, my ass.
Are you all nuts?
Did you already forget that someone died?
Are you against the result?
What? "Taking part in murder?"
Murder is killing a human being,
not a monster!
Honey.
Honey…
This is…
It's because I'm tired.
-Don't come near us!
-Don't!
It's because I'm tired!
You better brace yourself.
What?
If you don't want to be eaten
by a monster.
You son of a bitch.
Do I have the right to vote?
If I put this in,
he'll be thrown out with me, right?
Am I right?
He looks like he's just a kid.
A handsome kid.
Didn't you see how much he bled
and still didn't die?
You can't judge someone on their looks.
Would he survive a shot to the head?
How can we kill him then?
-Can we?
-How can you…
Did you vote in favor?
You're the murder accomplices.
What if he turns into a monster?
Will you leave him like that?
Can someone explain
why this is happening?
Is it because of a virus?
It's because of radiation.
Come on. Didn't you guys watch the news?
It's because of human desire.
Right. It must be because the owner
of the supermarket is so greedy.
Then what about Hyun-su?
What was his desire?
You better be careful, too.
It seemed your appetite
was out of control.
-It's because of radiation.
-Radiation?
We're getting punished.
It's God's punishment.
Yes. I agree.
That's the most plausible answer
I've heard so far.
Since we're all humans,
no one knows…
who will be next.
What?
Why am I…
You had a nosebleed and fainted.
I think it's pretty obvious.
That can't be…
Why now?
Why?
Well…
I hear you're holding out.
How are you doing it?
How?
You're shameless.
I have to live. I want to live.
Pull yourself together.
What?
I have nothing else to tell you.
It's a good thing. Don't you think?
He beat you every day.
What? Did I say something wrong?
Divorcees are considered hot these days.
A new life lies before you.
Excuse me.
I can't find Su-ung anywhere.
Oh, my… I guess you haven't heard.
Ms. Cha's daughter
really came back.
And Su-ung went out to rescue her.
He barely took a few steps.
Whoosh! It got him.
We're stuck here.
GREEN HOME HAIR SALON
SANG-WON
Sang-won…
Here.
You must be starving.
Thank you.
Eat this and cheer up.
I'm sorry I stared.
Eat up.
What's wrong?
Is something wrong with it?
It tastes okay.
My stomach is a little upset.
She's very pretty.
Did you take many pictures of her?
I only took a few.
That's what I regret.
He was a good person.
You need energy to miss someone.
Is this funny to you?
You should quit music
and become a comedian.
Why don't you teach me then?
First, relax your body.
Spread your legs shoulder-width apart.
Keep your hands close.
Don't take your eyes off the ball.
It's disgusting to see you act nice.
Do you think a frigging chocolate bar
can cheer her up?
You did that to make yourself feel better.
Are you the crazy bitch around here?
Fine. Go head, you crazy bitch.
He doesn't die?
You're here?
You said see you again, son of a bitch!
Wait a minute.
I have something to say.
I…
I think I've turned into a monster.
Please lock me up.
When did you get here?
Did you see the news?
It's not infectious.
We're still fucked, though,
because the world is doomed.
Moron.
He really looks like he got beat up.
He's the one who wants to be locked up.
Why did it happen to such a good man?
If you feel that bad,
you can get in there with him.
That's not the reason, is it?
Jeez.
Good morning.
You must be hungry.
I'm good.
What?
A monster can't eat?
You sleep well, though.
What does it feel like?
You feel so powerful, don't you?
How can I become like that?
Tell me.
I can do it really well.
What should I do?
Here.
You can take it.
PREGNANCY TEST
It's okay.
You never know.
Just in case.
Okay?
PREGNANCY TEST
Amen.
It was your voice, wasn't it?
"The first floor is quite safe for now."
Yes.
Did I hear you wrong?
That shield.
Who made it?
Mister.
What?
Ms. Im…
still hasn't come out of the bathroom.
Do you need to poop?
How long has she been in there?
It's been about an hour.
Okay. Step aside for a bit.
BASED ONSWEET HOME
BY CARNBY KIM AND YOUNGCHAN HWANG
Subtitle translation by Soo-hyun Yang
Modify by Blue-Bird™